

# **CONTACT**



+91-9920610445



rajesh\_shankar@rediffmail.com



Mumbai, Maharashtra





linkedin.com/in/rajesh-singh-

02248713/

#### **EDUCATION**

**Masters of Business Administration** (MBA-Finance) **University of Pune** 1995-1997

**Bachelor of Commerce** University of Pune 1992-1995

#### **OTHER-COURSES**

- "Honors Diploma in Computer Programming" from ICIT with "A" Grade (1995)
- "DIM" from Prin. L.N.W.M.D.R Matunga with "A+" Grade.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- NISM
- IRDA (Insurance Module)

### **SKILLS**

- Excellent Organizational, Negotiations skills
- Multi-Tasker, Team-Work, Team-Management, Goal Focused
- Motivated, Humble, Creative Thinking, Focused
- Communication, Presentation
- Microsoft Office

# Languages Known

English, Hindi, Marathi

# Rajesh Singh

#### **VP & Head-Sales & Business Development**

#### **PROFILE**

An MBA graduate with more than 22 years of experience in Retail sales, Banking channel sales, Institutional and PSU segment, Asset Management Companies, PSU-Pvt. JV Mutual Fund Companies, Customer handling, Operations setting-up branch, Financial planning, Forex & Team-management. Handled various geographical locations and also set up businesses.

Has been part of all phases of the MF Industry and handled all domains of business along with the representation to the Board, P&L domain of each segment, Merger and JV's and also worked in Public and Private Institutions.

Self-motivated with proven abilities in identifying and developing market thrust areas and undertaking promotional activities in the area to improve performance. Recognized with rewards for excellent performance in all diversified roles/positions.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Head - Sales and Business Development BOI AXA Investment Managers | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Feb 2019 -

Strategy to set up an effective business model and grow geographically, finding product gaps & launching new products to cover baskets of domain, maintaining cost and generating business with profits, generating revenue sales and improve profits.

- Within a year launched a new product and mobilized ever highest collection in NFO i.e. approx. Rs 165 Cr
- Launched new Equity schemes in lockdown period and successfully closed with mobilizations of approx. Rs 32 Cr with more than 1200 investors, Almost 50:50 contributions from BOI channel and Non-BOI channel
- In a period of one year, more than 12 circulars/promotional campaigns were issued to promote sale. Monthly login day scheduled has been formalized and two login days started to promote sales.
- Enhanced monthly transactions from 1000 to 4000-5000 transactions monthly, highest ever SIP enrollment in a month.

#### **Head-Institutional Sales & Channel Partners** BOI AXA Investment Managers | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Aug 2012 – Feb 2019

Strategy to set up institutional sales/business, product positioning and launch new products, put team in place, pricing and tie-up with channel partners, Acquisition of new customer/investors.

- Within Four months Debt fund AUM/Institutional business grew from Rs 5cr to 1000cr.
- Within Three years AUM grew to approx. Rs 6300cr.

#### **Head – Key Accounts – Institutional Sales (Debt & Equity)** L&T Investment Management Ltd | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Dec 2010 - Aug 2012

Strategy to achieve market share with top 50 clients, focus to strengthen relations with key partners/investors, pricing for key partners & training activities for sales team, presentation to Board, product designing & positioning.

- Successfully set-up team in Mumbai, Delhi & Ahmedabad with the growth of average Assets by 100%
- 435 new breakthroughs' (Corporate/Institutions/Banks/SME's & Trusts) in one year.
- AMC ranking improved from 25th to 22nd and Debt fund AUM ranking improved from 27<sup>th</sup> to 21<sup>st</sup>.
- In five months, AMC become 4<sup>th</sup> fastest in % terms and 6<sup>th</sup> fastest in absolute number terms growing AMC.
- Show your accomplishments by using numbers and percentages.

#### Head -Banking Channel (MNC, Pvt Banks & Alternate Channel sales) *P Paribas AMC |* Mumbai, Maharashtra| Dec 2007

Improving the Banking Channel Business, Team set-up, due to diligence process interactions with banks product/research team, negotiation of commercials to promote products, product training, AMFI training program to PSU & Co-operative banks/RM, Product positioning to achieve numbers.

- Achieved 5.50% market share of Equity sales of the banking channels industry business.
- Within a year, 18 New MOU signed with new banks and successfully achieved 100% products/schemas approvals in MNC Banks for distribution/sales.
- In a year, Industry Market share increased from 2.9% to 4.39% (Dec-2008)
- Banking channel sales contribution increased from 16% to 27% of AUM (Dec-2008)

## **Chief Manager in Charge (Corporate/Institutional Business)** SBI Funds Management (P) Ltd. | Mumbai, Maharashtra | June 2006 – Nov 2007

Strengthening the relationship with Institutional investor's, improve the corporate & institutional business, product innovation for the corporate & institutional investors, presentation for PMS, business development, ensure predefined practices in sales and service, resulting in complete satisfaction.

- In 3 months substantial increase in Debt fund corpus by launch of series of SBI Debt Funds Schemes.
- With 3 months, liquid fund corpus grew by 37%.

# Senior Manager (Branch Head)

SBI Funds Management (P) Ltd. | Kolkata, West Bengal | Dec 2005 – May 2006

Identify and develop market thrust areas and undertaking promotional activities, develop & appoint Dos, empanelment of IFA, distributors & channel partners, responsibility of productivity levels & service levels of channels, ensure predefined practices in sales & service, responsibility of overall control function of branch.

- Received a Best Performing Branch Head Award.
- Received two fold promotions to Senior Manager.
- Appointed DO in Durgapur & developed Burdwan, Asansol, Bankura & Purulia area successfully.
- Enlarged agent's strength from 195 to 1400 within one & half year. ISC Kolkata topped all branches in the number of applications in Magnum COMMA
- Fund NFO. Achieved highest ever mobilization in NFO from Kolkata.

#### Senior Relationship Manager (Branch Head)

SBI Funds Management (P) Ltd. | Pune & rest of Maharashtra (excluding mumbai) | April 2004 - Nov 2005

Identify and develop market thrust areas and undertaking promotional activities, set up branches (ISD) in Nagpur & Nashik, corporate presentation, responsible for productivity levels & service levels of channels, training programs for IFA, SBI branches & distributors, responsibility of the overall control function of the branch.

- Successfully started Nagpur & Nashik branches with 200% growth in volume within 5 months.
- Developed new areas Jalgaon, Ichhalkaranji, Satara & Kolhapur.

# Senior Relationship Manager (Branch Head) SBI Funds Management (P) Ltd. | Panaji, Goa| Dec 2001 – April 2004

Set-up Goa operations, corporate presentation, business development, responsibility of productivity levels, overall control function of branch, bank reconciliation & MIS reports.

- Goa branch become leader in Mutual Fund Industry from state within 2 years.
- Extended operations in Ratnagiri, Sindhdurg (Maharashtra).

#### **Assistant Manager (Sales & Distribution)**

Anand Rathi Securities (P) Limited | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Dec 1999 - Dec 2001

Financial Planning / advisory services, promotion of equity, mutual fund, fixed deposits, bonds, IPO's depository service & insurance products through HNI, corporate, Trusts, subbrokers, channel partners, institutions & NRI, conduct product promotion activities for associations and channel partners in the region, arrangement of IPO's financing through banks & NBFC's, preparation of MIS reports.

- Raised US \$20 million for the State Bank of India Millennium Deposit as sub-arranger with cost effectiveness.
- Book built public issue of TIPS Industries Ltd & Aksh Optifibre ITD with 18 and 12 bidding centers all over India.
- Successfully setup distribution networks in Maharashtra and Surat.

#### Executive – Customer Service (Forex)

*Transcorp International Limited (TCI Group)* | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Jan 1998 - Dec 1999

Develop liaison with corporate, HNI, travel agents, hotels, banks, customers and R.B.I and FFMC, promotion of Western Union Financial Services, prepare M.I.S report of the Mumbai branch for submission to H.O, recoveries of banks, negotiation with banks, travel agents and FFMC for pickup and offloading the various currencies.

 Successfully recovered outstanding of the branch and developed excellent liaison with Banks, Travel agents & FFMC